

DESIGNER / DEVELOPER

www.ethayer.co 619 952-5081

ethayer.design@gmail.com

Summary

More than ten years of design and multimedia experience working in video production and web development. Since moving to Denver I have worked with small and large companies with a focus on visual design and front-end development.

I want to be a key contributor to a brand/product management, design or development team, that cares deeply about accessibility, communication, and performance based UI/UX solutions.

Skills & Abilities

WEB DESIGN / FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

HTML5 • CSS3 • SCSS • JavaScript • CMS Integration

I develop responsive UI display patterns with performance and accessibility in mind. I enjoy creating design systems, front-end architecture and inclusive UX. I am comfortable with modern front-end frameworks or can provide custom development.

TOOLS: VS Code, Grunt/Gulp, Git/SVN, CodePen, Pattern Lab

VISUAL / USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN

Branding • Logos • UI • IxD • User Discovery • Prototypes

I have experience working in print, online and video design mediums. I believe that *good* research and discovery produce the best outcome. Communication is vital to my process and I enjoy working closely with creative teams to shape the final result.

TOOLS: InVision, Sketch, Adobe CC (AE, AI, PS, XD)

CONTENT STRATEGY / ART DIRECTION

IA • Wireframes • Layout • Styleguides • CMS Integration

I find that concept creation and prototyping are the most exciting part in the design process. I build interactive wireframes and code based mockups and enjoy developing the creative direction behind the style and layout of page "content" or interactive elements.

TOOLS: Adobe XD, HTML/CSS/JS, Kentico, Umbraco

CODEPEN codepen.io/ericthayer

GITHUB

github.com/ericthayer

Education

B.S. Media Arts - Platt College, San Diego, CAGraduated 2005 - focus: Video Production / Motion Graphics

A.A.S. Graphic Design - Platt College, San Diego, CA

Graduated 2003 - focus: Graphic / Web Design

Experience

7/2015 - current

Freelance Designer - ethayer.co

UI/UX Designer / Front-end Developer

- Produced 2 front-end design systems for rapid Kentico development
- · Established custom CSS framework for rapid prototyping
- Developed front-end architecture for 3 startups
- Created interactive wireframe and HTML based prototype template
- Successfully revised 2 non-responsive code bases

2011 - 2015

The Navigators - navigators.org

Lead Designer / Front-end Developer - responsible for the design and development of organizational creative needs including: logo/branding creation, UI/UX design, customer support, client consultation and project management.

- Delivered 40+ responsive websites for internal departments and missions
- Optimized 20+ existing non-responsive websites for mobile use
- Created Bootstrap based framework for rapid Kentico CMS development
- Decreased development time by 40% with custom template system
- Eliminated the need for design and development outsourcing
- Established front-end documentation and guide lines for client discovery
- Served on IT department communications board

2010 - 2013

Defense Language Institute - dliflc.edu

Multimedia Specialist - responsible for the creation of training videos, motion/web graphics and iOS UI/content across multiple teams for the Department of the Army (Defense Foreign Language Center).

- Delivered 100+ training videos and graphic materials
- Contributed to the production of over 50+ iOS training applications
- Increased graphic optimization time by 35% with custom process
- Introduced very first responsive website template system
- Optimized 5+ existing non-responsive websites for mobile use
- · Awarded commendation of service for "efficiency" 3 times

2005 - 2008

Multi-Image Productions - multiimage.com

Post Production Artist - responsible for motion graphics, video editing and DVD authoring for live event production company for clients like: Pizza Hut, American Airlines, MasterCard, NCR and Pitney Bowes.

- Designed 20+ live event motion graphic themes and assets
- Produced 50+ DVD user interfaces and packaging templates
- · Assistant video editor for a feature IMAX film Proud American
- Contributed on location shoots and with equipment setup and operation

Training

2013 - CSS Summit, CSSDevConf • 2014 - ArtifactConf + Atomic Design workshop, Platform14, SassSummit • 2015 - CSSDevConf, SassSummit 2016 - RWD Summit, Front Utah, CSSDevConf (volunteer) 2017 - SVG Summit, Front Utah